<!-- src/main/resources/META-INF/plugin.xml -->
<idea-plugin url="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA">
    <id>com.adobe.clawdea</id>
    <name>ClawDEA</name>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA" email="spopescu@adobe.com">ClawDEA</vendor>
    <description><![CDATA[
<p><b>ClawDEA gives <a href="https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/claude-code">Claude Code</a> a
self-maintaining understanding of your project.</b> Its standout capability is a project wiki that
stays in sync with your code, ships an orientation primer with every turn, and is ready to share across
a team via git &mdash; so Claude starts every conversation already knowing how your codebase works.</p>

<p>Most Claude plugins wrap the CLI in a chat window. ClawDEA goes further: a living knowledge layer plus
JVM profiling as a diagnostic loop, on top of IDE-grade code navigation, edit review, and debugging.
The result is an AI pair programmer that reasons from a maintained model of your project, profiles a slow
test and proposes a source-level fix, and navigates by reference instead of regex.</p>

<p><b>See it in action:</b> the <a href="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA#clawdea">README</a> has a live
demo of Claude autonomously debugging a Java application &mdash; setting breakpoints, stepping, inspecting
variables, and mutating runtime state to verify hypotheses.</p>

<h2>What makes ClawDEA different</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>A self-maintaining project wiki.</b> A project-local wiki under <code>.claude/wiki/</code> plus an
  auto-generated <code>REPO_STATE.md</code>. A commit-driven drift detector notices when a page's claims go
  stale and a bundled <code>wiki-author</code> subagent drafts the fix &mdash; with auto-update enabled it
  lands edits unattended. The primer ships with every turn so Claude starts each conversation oriented
  &mdash; no "let me explore the codebase first". A <code>wiki-librarian</code> subagent answers design
  questions in its own fresh context, citing pages and verifying against current source.</li>

  <li><b>Team-ready knowledge sharing.</b> Run <code>/wiki-relocate docs/llm-wiki</code> to commit the wiki
  path to <code>.clawdea/config.json</code>; teammates auto-discover the shared wiki on clone, with per-user
  vs team-shared drift state split automatically. Cross-repo navigation for monorepos via
  <code>.clawdea-workspace.md</code> and sibling-repo tools.</li>

  <li><b>JVM profiling as a diagnostic loop.</b> One-click profiling of tests and run configurations via
  JDK Flight Recorder. Claude analyzes CPU hotspots, allocation pressure, and memory leaks (.jfr and .hprof),
  then proposes source-level fixes. Entry points: <code>/profile</code> slash command, gutter icon on
  <code>@Test</code> methods, or imported recordings.</li>

  <li><b>IDE-grade code navigation, debugging &amp; edit review.</b> IntelliJ's PSI index as MCP tools
  (<code>find_usages</code>, <code>find_callers</code>, <code>find_implementations</code>,
  <code>find_supertypes</code>, <code>resolve_symbol</code> and more &mdash; precise and complete, not
  grep), a 21-tool live debugger with breakpoint-ownership tracking, and diff-gated edit review.
  <b>Coexists with IntelliJ's own bundled MCP server:</b> enable it and ClawDEA drops the few overlapping
  tools, keeping everything the IDE has no equivalent for (the usage/caller/type-hierarchy graph,
  ownership-tracked debugging, diff-gated edits, profiling, and the knowledge layer). Detection is
  fail-open.</li>
</ul>

<h2>The rest of the toolkit</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>Native edit review.</b> Each proposed change opens IntelliJ's diff dialog with Accept/Reject.
  A fallback coordinator catches built-in Edit/Write calls that bypass MCP and adds inline buttons with
  file revert, so Claude cannot silently overwrite your work.</li>

  <li><b>Inline completions.</b> Tab-completions powered by the Claude API with editor context from the
  context engine. Falls back to <code>claude -p</code> when no API key is configured.</li>

  <li><b>Intention actions (Alt+Enter).</b> Explain, Optimize, Generate Test, Security Check, Add
  Documentation, Refactor with Instructions, Ask Claude, Fix with Claude.</li>

  <li><b>Chat panel.</b> Streams responses with Markdown, tool-use cards, and clickable code references
  that navigate to source. Supports Auto, Plan, and Ask modes. <code>@</code>-mention for inline file and
  symbol picking, backed by IntelliJ's filename and short-name caches.</li>

  <li><b>Tool-call permissions.</b> Three modes (Confirm all / Allow safe / Allow all), with honoring of
  Claude Code's <code>permissions.allow</code> / <code>permissions.deny</code> rules. Permission cards
  block the CLI inline until you decide.</li>

  <li><b>Slash commands + Claude Code skills.</b> Built-ins (<code>/stop</code>, <code>/clear</code>,
  <code>/mode</code>, <code>/cost</code>, <code>/compact</code>, <code>/resume</code>, <code>/profile</code>,
  <code>/callers</code>, <code>/usages</code>, <code>/implementations</code>, <code>/supertypes</code>,
  <code>/note</code>, <code>/promote-to-wiki</code>) plus Claude Code skills discovered at runtime.</li>

  <li><b>Session resume.</b> Pick up a previous session with conversation history replayed in the chat panel.</li>

  <li><b>Auth flexibility.</b> API key, Claude subscription sign-in, AWS Bedrock, or Google Vertex.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Staying in sync with Claude Code</h2>

<p>ClawDEA wraps the Claude Code CLI as a subprocess and runs a weekly drift-monitoring job that diffs
<code>claude --help</code>, npm versions, and selected docs against a moving snapshot, plus a PR-time
fixture-replay test over a recorded stream-json transcript. Upstream changes to the CLI get caught by
CI, not by users.</p>

<h2>Getting started</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Install the CLI: <code>npm install -g @anthropic-ai/claude-code</code></li>
  <li>Install this plugin.</li>
  <li>Open <b>Settings &rarr; Tools &rarr; ClawDEA</b> and configure an Anthropic API key, sign in with a
  Claude subscription, or configure AWS Bedrock / Google Vertex credentials.</li>
  <li>Open the chat panel (<b>Tools &rarr; Toggle ClawDEA Chat</b>) and start coding.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Requirements</h2>

<ul>
  <li>IntelliJ IDEA 2026.1+</li>
  <li>Java 21 on the IDE's JBR (bundled)</li>
  <li>Claude Code CLI installed</li>
  <li>Anthropic API key, Claude subscription, or AWS Bedrock / Google Vertex credentials</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA">GitHub</a>
&middot; <a href="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA/blob/main/docs/user-guide.md">User guide</a>
&middot; <a href="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA/issues">Report an issue</a></p>

<p><i>ClawDEA is licensed under Apache 2.0. "Claude" and "Claude Code" are trademarks of Anthropic, PBC.
"IntelliJ", "IntelliJ IDEA", and "JetBrains" are trademarks of JetBrains s.r.o. ClawDEA is an independent
integration and is not affiliated with or endorsed by Anthropic or JetBrains.</i></p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
<h3>1.9.1</h3>
<h4>The chat adapts when docked horizontally</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Responsive layout for bottom/top docks.</b> When the ClawDEA tool window is docked along the bottom or top edge (short and wide), the top and bottom control bars merge into a single compact row and the input shrinks, so the scarce height goes to the conversation. Docked left/right it keeps the full two-row layout, and it re-arranges automatically as you re-dock or drag the splitter.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Fixes</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>The activity hint no longer disappears on long conversations.</b> On a long-running chat, a slow first response after a tool result could trip an internal watchdog that tore the turn down while the CLI was actually still working &mdash; leaving activity with no visible &ldquo;Thinking&rdquo; hint (with or without sub-agents). The turn now self-heals the moment output resumes, the watchdog is more patient before intervening, and a slow shell-environment probe can no longer fail a session resume or restart.</li>
  <li><b>&ldquo;Reset all-time&rdquo; in Cost Control now clears everything.</b> The reset button covers both estimated savings and measured knowledge upkeep, but it only cleared the estimate &mdash; leaving a stale upkeep figure and &ldquo;Overall&rdquo; total behind. It now clears both.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.9.0</h3>
<h4>See whether ClawDEA is saving you money</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Estimated Savings / Cost in the Cost Control panel.</b> A new section estimates the net dollar effect of ClawDEA&rsquo;s knowledge layer and IDE integration versus a standard Claude Code setup &mdash; the wiki librarian keeping exploration out of the main context, the IDE index replacing file reads &mdash; netted against what the layer costs to run (wiki/workspace upkeep and the per-turn primer). It shows this chat, this month, and all-time, each with a confidence range.</li>
  <li><b>Honest by design.</b> The estimate is a directional comparison against a baseline we don&rsquo;t actually run, and it can go negative: a short, one-shot session may cost more than it saves, and the panel says so &mdash; the section title flips to &ldquo;ClawDEA Estimated Cost&rdquo; when the all-time net is negative. Estimated lines carry a &plusmn; range; measured costs do not.</li>
  <li><b>Refines on resume.</b> Live sessions show a conservative floor (per-subagent costs aren&rsquo;t observable mid-stream); reopening a conversation reconstructs the full session from its transcript for a sharper estimate.</li>
  <li><b>Knowledge upkeep moved.</b> The standalone &ldquo;Knowledge upkeep&rdquo; card is now a line inside the new section, so its cost is netted in one place instead of shown separately.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Parallel sub-agents you can actually follow</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Live sub-agent panels are pinned and stack.</b> When Claude delegates to sub-agents, each one gets its own panel pinned to the bottom of the chat so it stays visible while it works &mdash; and when several run in parallel, their panels stack there instead of scrolling out of view. A panel only rejoins the normal conversation flow (collapsed to a one-line summary with its step count) once that sub-agent finishes.</li>
  <li><b>No more output broken mid-phrase.</b> Sub-agent reasoning no longer bleeds into the main answer: parallel sub-agent activity used to cut Claude&rsquo;s reply off mid-sentence and could make the progress dots disappear while work was still going. The main reply now stays intact, and each panel shows a live &ldquo;running &middot; N steps&rdquo; progress line.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Spend tokens on completions only when you ask</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Manual completion hotkey.</b> A new <b>Trigger Inline Completion</b> action (default <b>Alt+\</b>, &#8997;\ on macOS) requests a suggestion on demand &mdash; it always works, even with automatic completions on. Rebind it in <b>Settings &rarr; Keymap &rarr; &ldquo;Trigger Inline Completion&rdquo;</b>.</li>
  <li><b>Optional manual-only mode.</b> Enable <b>&ldquo;Only request completions on hotkey&rdquo;</b> in Settings to suppress as-you-type completions entirely, so API tokens are spent only when you press the hotkey. Off by default &mdash; automatic completions are unchanged unless you opt in.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Fixes and polish</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>The activity hint stays put during long and parallel work.</b> The pulsing &ldquo;Thinking&rdquo; dots no longer vanish mid-turn &mdash; they are re-asserted on each message and tool result and kept animating through long, quiet stretches, so a slow or parallel sub-agent run always shows that something is happening.</li>
  <li><b>Chat view recovers after sleep or a display change.</b> When the machine wakes from sleep or you (un)plug a monitor or move the window between displays, the chat could freeze or render at half resolution and never recover. ClawDEA now rebuilds the view automatically (and <code>/refresh-view</code> forces it), replaying the conversation into a fresh, responsive surface.</li>
  <li><b>Cost Control numbers reconcile and always show.</b> The savings section now adds up &mdash; estimated per-lever savings, measured upkeep, and a single &ldquo;Overall&rdquo; bottom line &mdash; and the all-projects, all-time aggregates show immediately on a brand-new chat instead of asking you to run a few turns first.</li>
  <li><b>IDE index-tools savings are no longer stuck at $0.00.</b> The first file read that the IDE index avoids is now priced at the full input rate (not the cache rate), so the estimated saving from index tools reflects the real cost avoided.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.8.1</h3>
<h4>Windows: chat starts reliably again</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Fixed: &ldquo;The command line is too long&rdquo; on Windows.</b> With the wiki librarian enabled, the chat could fail to start on Windows &mdash; the helper subagents were passed to the Claude CLI as a long inline argument that exceeded the Windows command-line limit. ClawDEA now launches the CLI in a way that isn&rsquo;t bound by that limit, so chat starts normally. macOS and Linux were unaffected.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.8.0</h3>
<h4>See &mdash; and control &mdash; what each turn costs</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Per-turn cost footer.</b> Every completed turn now shows the model it ran on, the effort level, the elapsed time, and the cost &mdash; e.g. <code>Opus 4.8 &middot; effort high &middot; 12.3s &middot; $0.0421</code>. The model and effort appear even under the &ldquo;Default&rdquo; selection, so you always know what actually ran.</li>
  <li><b>Cost shown on subscription and Bedrock too.</b> When your plan reports no per-turn dollar figure (subscription, and often Bedrock), the cost is computed from token usage with a per-model rate table, so the running total still moves.</li>
  <li><b>Per-chat running total.</b> Each chat tab tracks its own &ldquo;chat&rdquo; spend independently. Reopening a past conversation reconstructs its accumulated cost and shows it at the bottom, just like a live turn.</li>
  <li><b>Cost Control panel.</b> Click the cost chip to open a panel showing, per provider you&rsquo;ve used: your subscription usage (spend limit or rate-limit windows, live from your Claude account), or your tracked Bedrock spend (this month and all-time). Below that: this chat&rsquo;s cost, a by-model breakdown, and a <b>Knowledge upkeep</b> breakdown of what wiki and workspace creation/updates have cost. The daily-budget control lives in the panel footer and still color-codes the chip as you approach it.</li>
  <li><b>Model selector labels the default.</b> Once a Default-selection turn has run, the model dropdown&rsquo;s &ldquo;Default&rdquo; entry shows what it resolved to &mdash; e.g. <code>Default (Opus 4.8)</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.7.1</h3>
<h4>Wiki authoring that actually lands, and a tidier project footprint</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Fixed: recorded wiki suggestions now get written.</b> When the wiki librarian recorded a &ldquo;missing concept&rdquo; suggestion, the page could sit unwritten &mdash; the authoring pass ran on a slow periodic tick (or got wedged) and sometimes reported success without producing a file. Recording a suggestion now kicks off authoring immediately, the author has more time to finish, and a page is verified on disk before the suggestion is marked done.</li>
  <li><b>No more leftover <code>claude</code> processes.</b> Background <code>claude -p</code> helper processes are now tracked and cleaned up when the plugin unloads or the IDE quits, instead of lingering after you close the IDE.</li>
  <li><b>Tidier project footprint.</b> ClawDEA's own per-project files (the default-mode wiki and the generated repo-state summary) now live under <code>.clawdea/</code> instead of <code>.claude/</code>, and existing projects are migrated automatically on startup &mdash; nothing to do by hand. The redundant <code>SIBLINGS.md</code> file is no longer written.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.7.0</h3>
<h4>Sub-agents are now first-class in the chat</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Sub-agents render as collapsible cards.</b> When Claude dispatches a sub-agent (the <code>Agent</code> tool), its work now appears as a single card titled by what the sub-agent was asked to do, instead of the sub-agent's tool calls flooding the transcript. The card auto-expands while the sub-agent runs &mdash; so you can watch its steps stream in &mdash; then collapses to a one-line summary when it finishes. Click the header to expand it again; click any inner step to see that step's output.</li>
  <li><b>Parallel sub-agents stay separate.</b> When several sub-agents run at once, each gets its own card and its own steps &mdash; no more interleaved confusion.</li>
  <li><b>Resumed sessions look right too.</b> Reopening a past conversation reconstructs the sub-agent cards and the to-do checklist, rather than leaving a row of empty tool badges.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Keep Claude working toward a goal</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b><code>/goal</code> support.</b> Set a completion condition with <code>/goal &lt;condition&gt;</code> and Claude keeps working across turns until a fast model judges it met &mdash; no need to prompt each step. A sticky <b>goal banner</b> shows the condition, how many turns it has run, and the evaluator's latest reason, updating after every turn; each evaluation also leaves a short inline note in the transcript.</li>
  <li><b>Stop it any time.</b> Click <b>Clear</b> in the banner (or run <code>/goal clear</code> / <code>/goal stop</code>) to halt a running goal immediately; the banner clears and a <code>&#10003; Goal achieved</code> note appears when the condition is met on its own.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.6.4</h3>
<h4>Wiki librarian no longer swallows its own answer</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Fixed: the librarian sometimes came back empty.</b> When the wiki librarian spotted a gap worth flagging for the next wiki refresh, its actual answer was getting dropped on the way back &mdash; you'd see only a terse &ldquo;logged a suggestion&rdquo; note instead of the explanation you asked for. The librarian now always returns its full answer, with the suggestion noted at the end.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.6.3</h3>
<h4>Smarter by default</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Baseline working defaults.</b> ClawDEA now adds a small, always-on set of working defaults to Claude's instructions &mdash; stay surgical (don't refactor or reformat code you weren't asked to touch; surface worthwhile improvements as a separate suggestion instead of folding them in silently), prefer the simplest change that works, verify before claiming done, and ask only when a request is genuinely ambiguous <em>and</em> guessing wrong is costly. These are values, not a mandated procedure, and your project's <code>CLAUDE.md</code> and any installed workflow skills always take precedence &mdash; so they raise the floor without getting in the way of more capable tooling. Toggle them off any time via <b>Settings &rarr; Tools &rarr; ClawDEA</b> (&ldquo;Inject baseline working defaults into system prompt&rdquo;).</li>
  <li><b>Tunable system prompts.</b> ClawDEA's core system prompts (MCP tool routing, wiki-librarian routing, edit-review) and the new baseline defaults now live in editable resource files rather than compiled into the plugin, so the prompt text can evolve with model generations.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.6.2</h3>
<h4>JetBrains MCP server coexistence</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>No more duplicate tool names.</b> When IntelliJ's bundled MCP Server plugin is installed and its server is enabled, ClawDEA stops registering four tool names that collide with JetBrains' surface: <code>search_text</code>, <code>find_files</code>, <code>resolve_symbol</code>, and <code>get_diagnostics</code>. Claude Code now sees one tool per name; ClawDEA's unique tools (<code>find_usages</code>, <code>find_callers</code>, <code>find_implementations</code>, all <code>debug_*</code>, all <code>propose_*</code>, profiling, wiki, workspace) remain available.</li>
  <li><b>Fail-open detection.</b> ClawDEA reads JetBrains' setting via reflection. If the setting class is renamed or otherwise unreadable, ClawDEA logs a WARN and keeps its full surface registered, so the plugin stays useful even after future JetBrains internal changes.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.6.1</h3>
<h4>Drift state no longer dirties the working tree</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Rebase / merge no longer abort with "unstaged changes".</b> The drift detector now skips <code>rescan</code> and <code>dismiss</code> while a git operation is in progress (<code>GitRepository.state != NORMAL</code>), so <code>.wiki-state.json</code> is never rewritten mid-rebase, mid-merge, mid-cherry-pick, or mid-revert.</li>
  <li><b>Idle ticks no longer write to disk.</b> <code>lastSyncedCommit</code> is now advanced only on the first-run baseline or when a rescan actually applies an event; routine ticks leave the field where it is. The team-shared <code>.wiki-state.json</code> stops appearing as a phantom modification after every commit, fetch, or branch switch.</li>
</ul>
<h3>1.6.0</h3>
<h4>Scala support</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Scala in the index tools.</b> <code>find_symbol</code>, <code>find_usages</code>, <code>find_callers</code>, <code>find_implementations</code>, <code>find_supertypes</code>, and <code>resolve_symbol</code> now work on Scala sources via a new <code>ScalaLanguageSupport</code>. Companion-class ambiguity is resolved with <code>multiResolve</code>, and import refs are resolved through the Scala plugin's own resolver so wildcard/aliased imports are followed correctly.</li>
  <li><b>Optional Scala-plugin integration.</b> When the IntelliJ Scala plugin is installed, ClawDEA loads <code>clawdea-scala.xml</code> and registers a <code>ScalaPluginPsiBridge</code> that powers <code>find_related_types</code> and a new Scala-specific MCP tool, <code>find_implicit_definitions</code>, listing implicit givens, val/def declarations, and extension blocks in a Scala file.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Build-tool adapter abstraction</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Pluggable build tools.</b> A new <code>BuildTool</code> interface and <code>BuildToolRegistry</code> let ClawDEA discover Gradle, Maven, sbt, and Mill projects uniformly. <code>FileCollector</code> and the diagnostics pipeline now route through this registry instead of hard-coded Gradle paths.</li>
  <li><b>Maven, sbt, Mill.</b> <code>MavenBuildTool</code> walks the module tree, dispatches Kotlin/Scala compile when the respective Maven plugins are present, and reads pom.xml via the new <code>PomReader</code> DOM helper. <code>SbtBuildTool</code> and <code>MillBuildTool</code> bring sbt and Mill projects into the same flow.</li>
  <li><b>Per-language compile dispatch.</b> Gradle now dispatches Scala to <code>compileScala</code>; <code>BuildTool.compileCommandFor</code> takes a <code>LanguageSupport</code> so each adapter picks the right task per language.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Diagnostics tier improvements</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>IntelliJ first, build-tool fallback.</b> <code>get_diagnostics</code> now prefers IntelliJ inspections and the in-process <code>CompilerManager</code> over a build-tool subprocess. A new <code>CompilerManagerDiagnostics</code> helper turns the async compile API into a sync result. Tier 2 returns a clean "No diagnostics found." on empty inspection results instead of falling through.</li>
</ul>
<h4>UX polish &amp; fixes</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Edit-status badges now match the Auto-allowed style; the "Ask unlisted" approval mode gets a question-dialog icon in settings.</li>
  <li>Chat: thinking indicator is force-repainted after hide so it never lingers as a ghost row.</li>
  <li>Wiki: drift bookkeeping picks up legacy <code>.drift-state.json</code> at custom wiki paths; MCP errors are now logged with full context.</li>
  <li>CLI: <code>CliEventParser</code> handles array-form <code>tool_result</code> content so structured tool outputs no longer render as empty.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.5.0</h3>
<h4>Wiki team mode</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Choose where the wiki lives.</b> The new <code>/wiki-relocate &lt;repo-relative-path&gt;</code> slash command moves the wiki out of <code>.claude/wiki/</code> into a path your team agrees on (e.g. <code>docs/llm-wiki/</code>) and writes <code>.clawdea/config.json</code>. Anyone who clones the repo automatically picks up the configured location &mdash; no setup needed. The relocate command shows an editable AskUserQuestion card with move/copy/none options so you can confirm before files are touched.</li>
  <li><b>Per-user vs team-shared drift state.</b> In team mode the wiki's drift bookkeeping splits into <code>&lt;wikiDir&gt;/.wiki-state.json</code> (committed: <code>lastSyncedCommit</code>, persistent suggestions) and <code>.clawdea/wiki-state.local.json</code> (gitignored: per-user dismissals, last scan, probe misses). Branch switching now correctly re-anchors drift detection without forgetting your personal dismissals.</li>
  <li><b>Commit-anchored drift detection.</b> <code>CommitWikiDriftDetector</code> now uses <code>lastSyncedCommit..HEAD</code> instead of a wall-clock window, so wiki drift survives rebases, force-pushes, and laptop downtime accurately.</li>
  <li><b>Single source of truth for the wiki path.</b> New <code>WikiLocator</code> project service routes every wiki-aware code path (MCP tools, drift, primer, suggestion writer, ChatPanel) through one resolver, with idempotent migration from the legacy <code>.drift-state.json</code> on first read in team mode.</li>
</ul>
<h4>/seed-wiki bootstraps both layers</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>One command to start.</b> <code>/seed-wiki</code> now also creates <code>CLAUDE.md</code> from a scoped template if missing, and appends a "## Wiki" section linking to the wiki index when CLAUDE.md is present but the link is not. Bootstrap of CLAUDE.md and the wiki concept pages happens in a single turn.</li>
  <li><b>Smart suggestions.</b> When CLAUDE.md or the wiki index are missing, the chat surfaces an info block with a clickable <code>/seed-wiki</code> link instead of the generic <code>/init</code> nudge. The link runs the command for you with one click.</li>
</ul>
<h4>UX polish</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Editable AskUserQuestion cards.</b> Multi-choice prompts can now include an optional freeform text input, so commands like <code>/wiki-relocate</code> can offer "use this default path or type your own" without two round trips.</li>
  <li><b>Per-kind drift icons.</b> The drift banner, digest, and refresh prompts now show distinct icons per drift kind (code-rename, manifest-stale, wiki-suggestion, commit-drift) via the new <code>DriftEventIcon</code> helper.</li>
  <li><b>Per-tool icons for wiki MCP tools.</b> <code>read_wiki_page</code>, <code>search_wiki</code>, and edits inside the wiki directory now render with wiki-specific icons in the chat tool header.</li>
  <li><b>Project tree refreshes after <code>/wiki-relocate</code></b> so moved/copied files show up immediately in the IDE.</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.4.3</h3>
<p><b>Multiple-choice questions no longer get stuck after a long delay.</b> When a multi-choice prompt sat open longer than the CLI's ~60 s permission round-trip cap (claude-code #50289), Claude finalised its turn as denied and would re-ask the same question on a follow-up "continue" instead of using your answer. Late answers are now re-injected as a synthetic user message so the conversation moves on with your selection; Skip likewise tells the model to proceed without an answer.</p>

<h3>1.4.2</h3>
<p><b>/resume now renders past sessions the way they actually looked.</b> Resumed conversations were showing empty Write tools, edits as bare paths under the wrong "You" label, and AskUserQuestion / Task widgets rendered completely differently from the live stream. The replay path now shares a single rendering pipeline with the live event stream, so what you see when you resume matches what you saw the first time. (<a href="https://github.com/adobe/ClawDEA/issues/7">#7</a>)</p>

<h3>1.4.1</h3>
<p><b>Auto-update wiki now actually edits the wiki.</b> When you turn on "Auto-update wiki on drift", the wiki-author subagent now lands its proposed changes to disk in the background. Previously the subagent ran but its edits never reached your wiki because it was waiting for a diff-approval dialog that nobody could see.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Recording wiki suggestions ("missingConcept", "staleConcept", "incompleteConcept" via the librarian) is now reliable &mdash; previously failed silently for some inputs</li>
  <li>The wiki-author runs in fully unattended mode, has access to the project's IntelliJ index tools (find_symbol, search_text, etc.), and inherits your auth (subscription / Bedrock / Vertex) just like the chat</li>
  <li>Failures are now logged with enough context (exit code, stderr) to tell you why a wiki update didn't land instead of failing silently</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.4.0</h3>
<h4>Wiki knowledge layer</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Agent-based wiki:</b> replaced system-prompt-based wiki usage with specialized sub-agents <i>wiki-librarian</i> and <i>wiki-author</i> &mdash; slimmer system prompt, always-fresh findings (no long-session decay), supports larger wikis with better coverage on big projects</li>
  <li><b>Wiki-librarian routing:</b> Claude now consults the wiki-librarian subagent before answering project-understanding questions, grounding answers in synthesized concept pages with verified source citations</li>
  <li><b>Wiki-author subagent:</b> replaces the dream-based wiki maintenance system with a commit-driven drift detector that identifies stale wiki claims from git history, and a wiki-author subagent that rewrites affected pages</li>
  <li><b>Drift banner suppression:</b> with "Auto-update wiki" enabled, wiki-author events are handled silently without surfacing the drift banner; only truly unresolvable events remain visible</li>
</ul>
<h4>Permission UX</h4>
<ul>
  <li><b>Multi-panel routing:</b> permission cards now appear in the chat tab that triggered the tool call instead of whichever tab is focused, fixing wrong-tab approvals in multi-tab projects</li>
  <li><b>Auto-allowed badge:</b> the "⚡ Auto-allowed" marker now shows reliably on fast tool calls (it was racing with the HTTP signal on sub-second tools)</li>
  <li><b>Compact permission card:</b> removed redundant tool name and input echo since that info is already visible in the tool header above</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.3.6</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Windows: CLI permission settings no longer crash the CLI</b> &mdash; cmd.exe was stripping double-quotes from <code>.cmd</code> shim arguments, mangling the inline permission JSON; settings are now passed via a temp file</li>
  <li><b>Windows: tool-call panels show just the filename</b> for Read/Write/Edit actions, matching macOS behavior (was showing the full <code>C:\\...</code> path)</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.3.5</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Windows: ClawDEA now finds the Claude CLI when IntelliJ is launched from the Start menu/Explorer</b> &mdash; probes <code>%APPDATA%\\npm</code>, <code>%LOCALAPPDATA%\\Volta\\bin</code>, <code>%USERPROFILE%\\.local\\bin</code>, and <code>C:\\Program Files\\nodejs</code>. PowerShell shims are transparently redirected to the sibling <code>.cmd</code></li>
  <li><b>Windows: <code>.cmd</code>/<code>.bat</code> shims now launch correctly</b> &mdash; the executability check no longer rejects them (Windows decides launchability via <code>PATHEXT</code>, not the executable bit)</li>
  <li><b>Large system prompts no longer overflow the OS command-line limit</b> &mdash; the appended system prompt is now written to a temp file and passed via <code>--append-system-prompt-file</code>, fixing crashes on Windows (32 KB limit) and risk on Linux (<code>ARG_MAX</code>) when the skill catalog or primer grows large</li>
  <li><b>Release workflow now attaches the signed plugin zip to GitHub releases</b> automatically</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.3.4</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Compatibility fix for JetBrains Marketplace: profiling no longer uses an internal API flagged by Marketplace moderation</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.3.3</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Refreshed plugin icons (Marketplace thumbnail + tool-window, light and dark)</li>
  <li>First JetBrains Marketplace release</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.3.2</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Knowledge-layer reasoning: path-aware wiki probe, invariant-first concept pages, correction capture</li>
  <li>New <code>find_symbol</code> MCP tool &mdash; resolve class/method/field names to definition locations via the PSI index</li>
  <li>Per-session tool-approval state fixed</li>
  <li>Stronger tool-routing guidance steers Claude toward the index tools and away from filesystem grep for code symbols</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.2.0</h3>
<ul>
  <li>JFR-backed profiling: CPU, allocations, memory leaks, .jfr/.hprof import, gutter icon on <code>@Test</code> methods</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.1.0</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Hardened tool-permission UX and CLI session reliability</li>
  <li>Drift monitoring for Claude Code CLI changes with weekly digest + PR-time fixture replay</li>
</ul>

<h3>1.0.0</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Initial public release for IntelliJ IDEA 2026.1</li>
</ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.java</depends>
    <depends>Git4Idea</depends>

    <!-- Optional integration: clawdea-scala.xml loads only when the
         org.intellij.scala plugin is installed. -->
    <depends optional="true" config-file="clawdea-scala.xml">org.intellij.scala</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <!-- Settings -->
        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.settings.ClawDEASettings"/>

        <!-- Auth Manager -->
        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.auth.AuthManager"/>

        <applicationConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            instance="com.adobe.clawdea.settings.ClawDEASettingsConfigurable"
            id="com.adobe.clawdea.settings"
            displayName="ClawDEA"/>

        <!-- Context Engine -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.context.ContextEngine"/>

        <!-- Filesystem Refresh Coordinator -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.chat.FilesystemRefreshCoordinator"/>

        <!-- Chat Auto-Resume State -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.chat.session.ChatAutoResumeState"/>

        <!-- MCP Server -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.mcp.McpServer"/>

        <!-- Wiki Locator -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.knowledge.wiki.WikiLocator"/>

        <!-- Handler-initiated Question Service (parks resolvers for /wiki-relocate etc.) -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.chat.permission.HandlerQuestionService"/>

        <!-- Debug Bridge -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.debug.DebugBridge"/>

        <!-- Cost Tracker -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.cost.CostTracker"/>
        <!-- Subscription usage: ONE app-level poll, fanned out to every project's CostTracker. -->
        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.cost.OAuthUsageService"/>
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.cost.OAuthUsageProjectLink"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.cost.OAuthUsagePollerStartupActivity"/>

        <!-- Drift Detection -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.knowledge.drift.DriftDetectionService"/>
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.knowledge.drift.DriftPeriodicScanner"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.knowledge.drift.DriftStartupActivity"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.knowledge.drift.DriftPeriodicScannerStartupActivity"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.mcp.McpServerStartupActivity"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.knowledge.ClawdeaArtifactMigrationActivity"/>

        <!-- Git Repository Change Subscriber (drives drift rescan on git events) -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.chat.GitRepositoryChangeSubscriber"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.chat.GitRepositoryChangeSubscriberStartupActivity"/>

        <!-- Language Support Registry (Java + Kotlin built-in) -->
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.language.LanguageSupportInitializer"/>

        <!-- Build Tool Registry (Gradle + Maven built-in) -->
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.buildtool.BuildToolInitializer"/>

        <!-- Claude Gateway -->
        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="com.adobe.clawdea.gateway.ClaudeGateway"/>

        <!-- Inline Completions -->
        <inline.completion.provider
            implementation="com.adobe.clawdea.completions.ClawDEACompletionProvider"/>

        <!-- Intention Actions (Alt+Enter) -->
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.ExplainCodeAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.OptimizeCodeAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.GenerateTestAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.SecurityCheckAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.AddDocumentationAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.RefactorWithInstructionsAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.intentions.AskClaudeAction</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>
        <intentionAction>
            <className>com.adobe.clawdea.actions.quickfix.FixWithClaudeIntention</className>
            <category>ClawDEA</category>
        </intentionAction>

        <!-- Chat Tool Window -->
        <toolWindow
            id="ClawDEA"
            anchor="right"
            secondary="true"
            canCloseContents="true"
            icon="/icons/clawdea.svg"
            factoryClass="com.adobe.clawdea.chat.ChatToolWindowFactory"/>

        <!-- Notifications -->
        <notificationGroup
            id="ClawDEA"
            displayType="BALLOON"/>

        <!-- Profiling Line Marker -->
        <codeInsight.lineMarkerProvider language="JAVA"
            implementationClass="com.adobe.clawdea.profiling.ui.ProfilingLineMarker"/>
    </extensions>

    <applicationListeners>
        <!-- Safety-net reaper: kills orphaned persistent CLI subprocesses on
             plugin unload (dynamic reinstall) and IDE close. -->
        <listener
            class="com.adobe.clawdea.cli.CliProcessReaper"
            topic="com.intellij.ide.plugins.DynamicPluginListener"/>
        <listener
            class="com.adobe.clawdea.cli.CliProcessReaper"
            topic="com.intellij.ide.AppLifecycleListener"/>
    </applicationListeners>

    <actions>
        <!-- Context Menu Group -->
        <group id="ClawDEA.EditorPopupMenu"
               class="com.adobe.clawdea.actions.menu.ClawDEAActionGroup"
               text="ClawDEA"
               popup="true">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </group>

        <action id="ClawDEA.ToggleChatPanel"
                class="com.adobe.clawdea.actions.shortcuts.ToggleChatPanelAction"
                text="Toggle ClawDEA Chat"
                description="Toggle focus between editor and ClawDEA chat panel">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>

        <action id="ClawDEA.NewChatSession"
                class="com.adobe.clawdea.actions.shortcuts.NewChatSessionAction"
                text="New ClawDEA Chat Session"
                description="Open a new ClawDEA chat session tab">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>

        <action id="ClawDEA.AbortResponse"
                class="com.adobe.clawdea.actions.shortcuts.PauseOrAbortAction"
                text="Pause or Abort ClawDEA Response"
                description="Pause the current Claude response; press again to fully abort">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>

        <action id="ClawDEA.TriggerCompletion"
                class="com.adobe.clawdea.completions.TriggerCompletionAction"
                text="Trigger Inline Completion"
                description="Request a ClawDEA inline completion at the caret on demand (works with 'manual trigger only' mode)">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="alt BACK_SLASH"/>
        </action>

        <action id="ClawDEA.ProfileRun" class="com.adobe.clawdea.profiling.ui.ProfilingRunAction"
            text="Run with ClawDEA Profiler" description="Profile the selected Run configuration">
            <add-to-group group-id="RunMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
        <action id="ClawDEA.ImportProfile" class="com.adobe.clawdea.profiling.ui.ImportProfileAction"
            text="Analyze with ClawDEA" description="Analyze this recording with ClawDEA profiler">
            <add-to-group group-id="ProjectViewPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
